<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>Hashing It Out Podcast</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/</link><description>Hashing It Out Podcast</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://hashing-it-out.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hashing It Out #50 – AVA Labs - Emin Gün Sirer</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-06-27-hashing-it-out-50/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-06-27-hashing-it-out-50/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="/images/50hio.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div>Welcome back, Dr. Sirer on our 50th episode! The Avalanche consensus protocol was released last year by a pseudonymous team of researches &ldquo;Team Rocket&rdquo; (no relation to Pokemon, our sources say). Dr. Emin Gün Sirer has been a strong proponent of the protocol and has developed an implementation under his company AVA Labs. With test TPS of 6500 on a realistic test environment, AVA is already showing speeds rivaling VISA on Black Friday.]]></description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #49 – xDAI Burner Wallet - Austin Griffith</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-06-21-hashing-it-out-49/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-06-21-hashing-it-out-49/</guid><description><![CDATA[With great pleasure, we present to you, Austin Griffith. You&rsquo;ve seen this man all over YouTube, often rockin&rsquo; a bowtie, and showing some amazing and dynamic live demonstrations of his creative process in designing new user experiences for Ethereum. Author of the xDAI burner wallet, expert in meta transactions, and dapp development pioneer, Austin&rsquo;s energy and knowledge is palpable. This episode is a lot of fun and highly educational.
Links - Austin&rsquo;s homepage - Austin Twitter - Burner Wallet Gitcoin Grant - Clevis - Dapparatus]]></description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #48 - MakerDAO pt. 2 - Nik Kunkel</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-06-05-hashing-it-out-48/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-06-05-hashing-it-out-48/</guid><description>MakerDAO has built a token that is reasonably stable with the USD. We have the great pleasure of interviewing Nik Kunkel, Head of Backend Services at Maker. In this Part 2 of 2 on Maker, we talk about the technical design behind developing Maker. Please listen to Part 1 of 2 (previous episode, #47) before this, as it&amp;rsquo;s essential for understanding the principles guiding the design decisions. This is compelling work, and truly amazing how well it&amp;rsquo;s standing against the throes of the fluctuating markets.</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #47: MakerDAO pt. 1 – Nik Kunkel</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-30-hashing-it-out-47/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-30-hashing-it-out-47/</guid><description>MakerDAO has built a token that is reasonably stable with the USD. We have the great pleasure of interviewing Nik Kunkel, Head of Backend Services at Maker. In this Part 1 of 2 on Maker, we talk about the cryptoeconomics behind creating a stable token pegged to the USD. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand this before getting into the technicals found in Part 2 of 2 (next episode, #48). This is compelling work, and truly amazing how well it&amp;rsquo;s standing against the throes of the fluctuating markets.</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #46: Ren - Loong Wang</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-24-hashing-it-out-46/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-24-hashing-it-out-46/</guid><description>We have CTO of Ren, Loong Wang, on to educate us on their token transfer protocol. Ren is building a system that allows a user to transfer a token from one change to another, without the drawbacks found in techniques like atomic swaps. They have a network of &amp;ldquo;dark nodes&amp;rdquo; which run on their virtual machine, RenVM, to computer across the transactions and share data over the network. Interesting technology with many use cases!</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #45: Cosmos Network - Zaki Manian</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-10-hashing-it-out-45/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-10-hashing-it-out-45/</guid><description>Champion of decentralization, Zaki Manian, rejoins us for updates on Cosmos since their Mainnet launch. We dive into the design principles of Cosmos, their consensus mechanisms, incentivisation model, and how to integrate your decentralized application into the Cosmos Network. We also learn more about who is currently using Cosmos and how, what Zaki and Cosmos will be speaking on at NYC Blockchain Week events, as well as how Cosmos differentiates itself from other technologies being produced.</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #44: Blockstream - Russell O'Connor</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-03-hashing-it-out-44/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-05-03-hashing-it-out-44/</guid><description>We bring you another brilliant mind on the show for this episode! Russell O&amp;rsquo;Connor, developer of Blockstream&amp;rsquo;s Simplicity programming language for Bitcoin, dives deep into formal verification topics. We learn about the language design principles driving Simplicity, how formal verification plays an integral role in making the language suitable for securely automating Bitcoin transactions, and the challenges in creating a smart contract script for Bitcoin. We get a glimpse into the future of blockchain automation, and he elucidates what is being done right and what could be done better in blockchain platforms to place security first in smart contract design.</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #43: Kadena - Stuart Popejoy and Emily Pillmore</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-04-26-hashing-it-out-43/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-04-26-hashing-it-out-43/</guid><description>We are excited to have the Kadena team back on with an update. The erudite Stuart Popejoy and brilliant Emily Pillmore speak more on Pact, the smart contract language with built-in formal verification used in the Kadena Chainweb. We learn more about formal verification: what it means, how it works, and a bit of its limitations. They also give us an update on Chainweb itself and talk us through some of the challenges since we last spoke&amp;hellip; AND their innovated solutions to those challenges!</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #42: Monero Research Lab - Brandon Goodell</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-04-12-hashing-it-out-42/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-04-12-hashing-it-out-42/</guid><description>We shouldn&amp;rsquo;t pick favorites, but this is definitely one of our favorite episodes so far. We have the extreme pleasure of learning from Brandon Goodell, Research Associate at Monero Research Lab, about Monero, how it&amp;rsquo;s designed, privacy in Monero and how it compares to other coins like ZCash, scalability, and consensus mechanisms in general. This is exactly the kinda conversations we built this show for, and there were more than one eye opening moments.</description></item><item><title>Hashing It Out #41: Harry Denley - MyCrypto</title><link>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-04-04-hashing-it-out-41/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author><name>Author</name></author><guid>http://hashing-it-out.github.io/posts/2019-04-04-hashing-it-out-41/</guid><description>Ahoy-hoy! Today we have Director of Security at MyCrypto, Harry Denley. We talk about phishing attacks! No, not assaults at jam band concerts, the kind where you lose your money. We go over the process of finding these attacks, reacting to them, and staying ahead of the scammers. We talk about the tools used to intercept and analyze these attacks, and the processes surrounding gathering the evidence against the attackers. Harry is doing amazing work, and he&amp;rsquo;s really putting effort into keeping us all safe.</description></item></channel></rss>